Guide to the Trigant Burrow Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Main Correspondence File, 1875-1983; Series I; 20.25' (49 boxes)
  - Photographs, 1900-1966, undated (Box 45, Folder 1210-1214)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 45, Folder 1215)
    - Ackley - Hatheway, 1919-1950, undated (Box 46, Folder 1216-1281)
    - Hawkins - Robinson, 1916-1950, undated (Box 47, Folder 1282-1331)
    - Rosenberg - Voegtlin, 1919-1949, undated (Box 48, Folder 1332-1373)
    - Wallach - Letters to Burrow, 1921-1950, undated (Box 49, Folder 1374-1389)
- Subsidiary Correspondence File, 1899-1950; Series II; 5.75' (14 boxes)
  Series II, SUBSIDIARY CORRESPONDENCE FILE, consists of correspondence, financial and business papers, memoranda, writings, and other materials primarily documenting Burrow's professional life, business activities, and legal affairs.
  The material is arranged under seven headings; within each subgroup, the files are found in alphabetical order.
  - Office Special
    - Blum, Bessie M.: outline for paper, undated (Box 50, Folder 1390)
    - Burrow, John Devereux, undated (Box 50, Folder 1391)
    - Camp Beau Rivage, 1922 (Box 50, Folder 1392)
    - Certificates: Dr. Burrow, 1899 (Box 50, Folder 1393)
    - "The Dream Interpreter:" copyright, 1914 (Box 50, Folder 1394)
    - Examinations, outlines of, undated (Box 50, Folder 1395)
    - "G" cross reference card, undated (Box 50, Folder 1396)
    - Galt, William Egleston, 1928 (Box 50, Folder 1397)
    - Germain, A. H., undated (Box 50, Folder 1398)
    - Guggenheimer, Aimée, undated (Box 50, Folder 1399)
    - "H" miscellaneous, undated (Box 50, Folder 1400)
    - "I" cross reference card, undated (Box 50, Folder 1401)
    - Kinder, Elaine Flitner: "Correcting for 'I'", undated (Box 50, Folder 1402)
    - Kinder, Elaine Flitner: Journal Club report, undated (Box 50, Folder 1403)
    - Lifwynn household, 1920-1922 (Box 50, Folder 1404)
    - Medical advice, 1922, 1925, undated (Box 50, Folder 1405)
    - New York lectures, 1918 (Box 50, Folder 1406)
    - Organic Psychology, 1922, undated (Box 50, Folder 1407)
    - "P" miscellaneous, undated (Box 50, Folder 1408)
    - Parker, Carleton H., 1917-1918 (Box 50, Folder 1409)
    - Parker, Cornelia (Box 50, Folder 1409)
    - Passports, 1925-1926 (Box 50, Folder 1410)
    - Poems, undated (Box 50, Folder 1411-1412)
    - Pope, Laura Spencer Portor, undated (Box 50, Folder 1413)
    - Psychoanalysis, by Elizabeth Kay, 1916 (Box 50, Folder 1414)
    - Reprints, 1897-1917 (Box 50, Folder 1415)
    - Seminar notes, 1926 (Box 50, Folder 1416)
    - Shields, Clarence, 1918-1936 (Box 50, Folder 1417)
    - Sill, Alfreda P.: "Isaac Newton and Mother Goose", undated (Box 50, Folder 1418)
    - Stein, Gertrude, undated (Box 50, Folder 1419)
    - Syz, Emily Sherwood Burrow, 1918, undated (Box 50, Folder 1420)
    - T_______, 1916-1917 (Box 50, Folder 1421)
    - Thompson, Charles Baker: "Emotional Factors in Education", 1925 (Box 50, Folder 1422)
    - Thompson, Charles Baker: "Mental Health from the Social Viewpoint", 1925 (Box 50, Folder 1423)
    - Financial
      - Blum, Bessie M., 1924-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1424)
      - Bruce, Rosalind, 1925-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1425)
      - Edwards, C. Bryant, 1925-1926 (Box 50, Folder 1426)
      - Galt, William Egleston, 1925-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1427)
      - Guggenheimer, Aimée, 1925-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1428)
      - Guggenheimer, Flora A., 1927 (Box 50, Folder 1429)
      - Hölljes, Nelly, 1925-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1430)
      - Huiskamp, John E., undated (Box 50, Folder 1431)
      - Kinder, Elaine Flitner, 1925-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1432)
      - Leigh, John Randolph, 1925-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1433)
      - Schroeder, Joanna A., undated (Box 51, Folder 1434)
      - Syz, Hans C., 1927 (Box 51, Folder 1435)
      - Thompson, Charles Baker, 1925-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1436)
  - Baltimore Office File
    - Office organization and memoranda, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1437)
    - Schedules and office conferences, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1438)
    - Blum, Bessie M., 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1439-1444)
    - Bruce, Rosalind, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1445)
    - Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan, 1926-1928 (Box 51, Folder 1446-1449)
    - Burrow, John Devereux, 1926-1928 (Box 51, Folder 1450-1451)
    - Edwards, C. Bryant, 1926-1928 (Box 51, Folder 1452-1453)
    - Galt, William Egleston, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1454)
    - Guggenheimer, Aimée, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 1455-1457)
    - Guggenheimer, Flora A., 1927-1928 (Box 51, Folder 1458)
    - Hölljes, Nelly, 1926-1927 (Box 52, Folder 1459-1462)
    - Huiskamp, John E., 1926-1927 (Box 52, Folder 1463-1468)
    - Kinder, Elaine Flitner, 1926-1928 (Box 52, Folder 1469-1472)
    - Leigh, John Randolph, 1926-1927 (Box 52, Folder 1473)
    - Schroeder, Joanna, 1927-1928 (Box 52, Folder 1474)
    - Shields, Clarence, 1926-1927 (Box 52, Folder 1475)
    - Syz, Hans C., 1926-1927 June (Box 52, Folder 1476-1483)
    - Syz, Hans C., 1927 August-1928 (Box 53, Folder 1484-1486)
    - Syz, Hans C.: miscellaneous, 1926 (Box 53, Folder 1487)
    - Thompson, Charles Baker, 1926-1927 (Box 53, Folder 1488-1494)
  - Norfolk file
    - "A" miscellaneous, 1927, 1933 (Box 53, Folder 1495)
    - Baetjer, Harry N., 1926-1936 (Box 53, Folder 1496-1500)
    - Burrow, Alan G., 1916-1922 (Box 53, Folder 1501)
    - Burrow, Anastasia Devereux, 1923, undated (Box 53, Folder 1502-1503)
    - Burrow, Geraldine Dickson, 1923-1942 (Box 53, Folder 1504-1505)
    - Burrow, Inez, 1923-1927 (Box 53, Folder 1506)
    - Burrow, Mary Bragg (Box 53, Folder 1506)
    - Burrow-Martin & Company, 1923-1940, undated (Box 53, Folder 1507)
    - Christian, Laura W., 1923-1925 (Box 54, Folder 1508)
    - Clippings, 1937-1941 (Box 54, Folder 1509)
    - Cruser, Hanford T., 1936-1945 (Box 54, Folder 1510)
    - "D" miscellaneous, 1941 (Box 54, Folder 1511)
    - "E" miscellaneous, 1933 (Box 54, Folder 1512)
    - "F" miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 1513)
    - "G" miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 1514)
    - "H" miscellaneous, undated (Box 54, Folder 1515)
    - "K" miscellaneous, 1940 (Box 54, Folder 1516)
    - Leases, 1919-1947 (Box 54, Folder 1517)
    - Memoranda, 1924-1946 (Box 54, Folder 1518)
    - National Bank of Commerce, 1927-1943 (Box 54, Folder 1519-1532)
    - National Bank of Commerce, 1944-1950 (Box 55, Folder 1533-1538)
    - Norfolk, city of, 1919-1927, undated (Box 55, Folder 1539)
    - Norfolk estate, 1926-1927 (Box 55, Folder 1540)
    - Norfolk trip: Burrow and Galt, 1935 (Box 55, Folder 1541)
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1926, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 1542)
    - Spindle, Richard Buckner, Jr., 1923-1941 (Box 55, Folder 1543-1546)
    - Trust Company of Norfolk, 1924-1931 (Box 55, Folder 1547-1552)
  - Business file
    - "A" general, 1931-1948 (Box 55, Folder 1553)
    - Accounts: students, 1927 (Box 55, Folder 1554)
    - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1939-1940 (Box 55, Folder 1555)
    - "B" general (Ba - Be), 1928-1949 (Box 55, Folder 1556)
    - "B" general (Bi - Bu), 1931-1949 (Box 56, Folder 1557)
    - Baetjer, Harry N., 1920-1935 (Box 56, Folder 1558-1561)
    - Booth, Frank J. & Company, 1938-1942 (Box 56, Folder 1562-1564)
    - Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan, 1927-1939 (Box 56, Folder 1565-1573)
    - Burrow, John Devereux, 1927-1938 (Box 56, Folder 1574-1577)
    - Bills and receipts, 1934 (Box 56, Folder 1578)
    - Burrow, Trigant: budgets, 1943-1949 (Box 56, Folder 1579)
    - "C" general, 1921-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1580-1581)
    - Cable code, 1928, 1937 (Box 57, Folder 1582)
    - Central Bureau for Registered Addresses, 1928-1937 (Box 57, Folder 1582)
    - Connecticut: Department of Health, 1927-1943 (Box 57, Folder 1583)
    - "D" general, 1924-1948 (Box 57, Folder 1584)
    - "E" general, 1929-1949 (Box 57, Folder 1585)
    - "F" general, 1922-1944 (Box 57, Folder 1586)
    - "G" general, 1925-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1587)
    - "H" general, 1920-1946 (Box 57, Folder 1588)
    - Hall and Harrison Insurance, 1924-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1589-1592)
    - Harris, Kerr, Forester & Company, 1928-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1593-1595)
    - "I" general, 1922, 1925 (Box 57, Folder 1596)
    - Irving Trust Company, 1927-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1597-1598)
    - "J" general, 1932-1948 (Box 57, Folder 1599)
    - "K" general, 1923, 1932 (Box 57, Folder 1600)
    - "L" general, 1928-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1601)
    - Leigh, John Randolph, 1926-1931 (Box 57, Folder 1602)
    - Lifwynn (Lake Station), 1913-1927 (Box 57, Folder 1603)
    - Lippincott, Samuel W., 1921-1922 (Box 57, Folder 1604)
    - "M" general, 1921-1947 (Box 57, Folder 1605)
    - "N" general, 1921-1950 (Box 58, Folder 1606-1607)
    - New York Telephone Company, 1926-1949 (Box 58, Folder 1608)
    - Oates, Malcolm N., 1937-1941 (Box 58, Folder 1609)
    - "P" general, 1918-1949 (Box 58, Folder 1610)
    - "R" general, 1926-1944 (Box 58, Folder 1611)
    - "S" general, 1932-1949 (Box 58, Folder 1612)
    - Sloan, James S., 1933-1945 (Box 58, Folder 1613-1618)
    - Social Security, 1936-1945 (Box 58, Folder 1619)
    - Syz, Emily Sherwood Burrow, 1927-1931, undated (Box 58, Folder 1620)
    - "T" general, 1922-1949 (Box 58, Folder 1621)
    - Taxes: federal, 1943-1948 (Box 58, Folder 1622)
    - Taxes: state and local, 1923-1935 (Box 58, Folder 1623)
    - Travel expenses, 1937, 1939 (Box 58, Folder 1624)
    - Travelers Insurance Company, 1931-1937 (Box 58, Folder 1625)
    - Tuscany-Lombardy Community Corporation, 1920-1945 (Box 58, Folder 1626-1631)
    - "U" general, 1933-1947 (Box 58, Folder 1632)
    - "V" general, 1933-1950 (Box 58, Folder 1633)
    - "W" general, 1930-1950 (Box 59, Folder 1634)
    - Water Department, Baltimore, 1926 (Box 59, Folder 1635)
    - Wechsler, Ralph V., 1928-1934 (Box 59, Folder 1636)
    - "Z" general, 1923-1934 (Box 59, Folder 1637)
  - Westport file
    - Batchelder, David H., 1939-1949 (Box 59, Folder 1638)
    - The Connecticut Light & Power Co., 1939, 1942 (Box 59, Folder 1639)
    - Daybreak Nurseries, 1941-1945 (Box 59, Folder 1640)
    - Highway, proposed, 1944-1945 (Box 59, Folder 1641)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1949 (Box 59, Folder 1642-1644)
    - Nash, Edward C., 1939 (Box 59, Folder 1645)
    - Punzelt, Philip M., 1939-1949 (Box 59, Folder 1646)
    - Summer Hill House, 1939-1949, undated (Box 59, Folder 1647-1652)
    - Wake, Hereward, 1939, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 1653)
  - Lifwynn Camp file
    - "A" general, 1924-1944, undated (Box 59, Folder 1654)
    - "B" general, 1925-1943 (Box 59, Folder 1655)
    - Bellows, C. C., 1919-1939 (Box 59, Folder 1656-1662)
    - Bellows, C. C., 1940-1944 (Box 60, Folder 1663-1665)
    - Business-financial, 1930-1931 (Box 60, Folder 1666)
    - "C" general, 1931-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1667)
    - Chateaugay Ore and Iron Company, 1938-1943 (Box 60, Folder 1668)
    - "D" general, 1942, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 1669)
    - Delaware and Hudson Railroad, 1942-1945 (Box 60, Folder 1670)
    - "E" general, 1943 (Box 60, Folder 1671)
    - "F" general, 1942 (Box 60, Folder 1672)
    - Fire prevention, 1927-1944, undated (Box 60, Folder 1673)
    - Fletcher & Brown, 1942-1944 (Box 60, Folder 1674-1675)
    - Forestry, 1923 (Box 60, Folder 1676)
    - "G" general, 1932-1948 (Box 60, Folder 1677)
    - Gray Marine Motor Company, 1935-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1678)
    - "H" general, 1932-1943 (Box 60, Folder 1679)
    - Hölljes, Nelly, 1931 (Box 60, Folder 1680)
    - Health department and sanitation, 1927-1944 (Box 60, Folder 1681)
    - Insurance: T. Heffernan & Son, 1922-1946 (Box 60, Folder 1682-1684)
    - "J" general, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 1685)
    - "K" general, 1937-1940 (Box 60, Folder 1686)
    - "L" general, 1934 (Box 60, Folder 1687)
    - Lifwynn Foundation, 1931-1933 (Box 60, Folder 1688)
    - "M" general, 1934-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1689)
    - Memoranda, 1923-1930 (Box 60, Folder 1690)
    - Merrill, Clare, 1943-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1691-1696)
    - Mikkelsen, Inc., 1938 (Box 60, Folder 1697)
    - Minutes, Camp Management Committee, 1930 (Box 60, Folder 1698)
    - "N" general, 1935-1944 (Box 61, Folder 1699)
    - New York, State of, Department of Taxation and Finance, 1935-1941 (Box 61, Folder 1700)
    - Office of Price Administration, 1943-1945 (Box 61, Folder 1701)
    - "P" general, 1925-1947 (Box 61, Folder 1702)
    - Personnel, 1923-1927 (Box 61, Folder 1703)
    - Poetry, 1928 (Box 61, Folder 1704)
    - "R" general, 1938-1943 (Box 61, Folder 1705)
    - Reilly, Marjorie E. Young, 1932-1949 (Box 61, Folder 1706-1909)
    - Replies to statement on opening Lifwynn Camp, 1930 (Box 61, Folder 1710)
    - "S" general, 1939-1944 (Box 61, Folder 1711)
    - Shutts, Lester, 1938-1940 (Box 61, Folder 1712)
    - Shutts, Maurice, 1945 (Box 61, Folder 1712)
    - Shutts, Roland, 1943 (Box 61, Folder 1712)
    - Solvay Sales Corporation, 1944-1948 (Box 61, Folder 1713)
    - Taxes: county and school, 1921-1945 (Box 61, Folder 1714)
    - Tennis court, 1930-1931 (Box 61, Folder 1715)
    - Tent houses, 1924-1926, undated (Box 61, Folder 1716)
    - "U" general, 1939 (Box 61, Folder 1717)
    - "V" general, 1943 (Box 61, Folder 1718)
    - "W" general, 1937, 1943 (Box 61, Folder 1719)
  - Mrs. Burrow's Letters
    - Correspondence, 1902-1919 (Box 61, Folder 1720-1733)
    - Correspondence, 1925-1949 (Box 62, Folder 1734-1755)
  - Formerly restricted
    - Baltimore Office File, 1926-1927 (Box 63, Folder 1756-1760)
    - Norfolk file, 1919-1941, undated (Box 63, Folder 1761-1774)
    - Series IV, Additional Papers,Table notes, 1926; Series IV (Box 63, Folder 1775)
- Manuscript File, 1904-1984; Series III; 12' (29 boxes)
  Series III, MANUSCRIPT FILE, contains twenty-nine boxes of writings of Trigant Burrow. The material is found under the headings of Printed Works, Boxes 64-67; Manuscripts of Published Works, Boxes 68-72; Published Books, Boxes 72-81; Sources for Posthumous Works, Boxes 81-87; and Unpublished Material, Boxes 87-92. Printed Works, Published Books, and Sources for Posthumous Works are arranged chronologically, while Manuscripts of Published Works is in alphabetical order and Unpublished Material is alphabetically and topically arranged.
  - Printed Works
    - "The Determination of the Position of a Momentary Impression in the Temporal Course of a Moving Visual Impression", 1909 (Box 64, Folder 1776)
    - "Hysterical Defects of Musical Language", 1909 (Box 64, Folder 1776A)
    - Freud's Psychology in its Relation to the Neuroses", 1911 (Box 64, Folder 1777)
    - "Some Psychological Phases of Medicine", 1911 (Box 64, Folder 1778)
    - "Conscious and Unconscious Mentation from the Psychoanalytic Viewpoint", 1912 (Box 64, Folder 1779)
    - "Psychoanalysis and Society", 1912-1913 (Box 64, Folder 1780)
    - "The Method of Psychoanalysis", 1913 (Box 64, Folder 1781)
    - "The Psychotherapeutic Treatment of the Functional Neuroses" by Llewellys F. Barker and Trigant Burrow, 1913 (Box 64, Folder 1781A)
    - "The Psychological Analysis of So-Called Neurasthenic and Allied States", 1913 (Box 64, Folder 1782)
    - "The Meaning of the Psychic Factor", 1913-1914 (Box 64, Folder 1783)
    - "Character and the Neuroses", 1914 (Box 64, Folder 1784)
    - "The Psychanalyst and the Community", 1914 (Box 64, Folder 1785)
    - "Permutations within the Sphere of Consciousness", 1916 (Box 64, Folder 1786)
    - "The Philology of Hysteria", 1916 (Box 64, Folder 1787)
    - "Conceptions and Misconceptions in Psychoanalysis", 1917 (Box 64, Folder 1788)
    - "The Genesis and Meaning of 'Homosexuality' and its Relation to the Problem of Introverted Mental States", 1917 (Box 64, Folder 1789)
    - "The Meaning of Psychoanalysis", 1917 (Box 64, Folder 1790)
    - "Notes with Reference to Freud, Jung, and Adler", 1917 (Box 64, Folder 1791)
    - "The Origin of the Incest-Awe", 1918 (Box 64, Folder 1792)
    - "Social Images Versus Reality", 1924 (Box 64, Folder 1793)
    - "The Camera Man", 1925 (Box 64, Folder 1794)
    - "Psychiatry as an Objective Science", 1925 (Box 64, Folder 1795)
    - "A Relative Concept of Consciousness", 1925 (Box 64, Folder 1796)
    - "Die Gruppenmethode in der Psychoanalyse", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1797)
    - "The Heroic Role: An Historical Retrospect", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1798)
    - "Insanity A Social Problem", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1799)
    - "The Laboratory Method in Psychoanalysis, Its Inception and Development", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1800)
    - "Our Mass Neurosis", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1801)
    - "Our Social Evasion", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1802)
    - "Penny Wise and Pound Foolish", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1803)
    - "Psychoanalysis in Theory and in Life", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1804)
    - "Psychoanalytic Improvisations and the Personal Equation", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1805)
    - "The Reabsorbed Affect and its Elimination", 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1806)
    - "An Ethnic Aspect of Consciousness", 1927 (Box 64, Folder 1807)
    - "The Group Method of Analysis", 1927 (Box 64, Folder 1808)
    - "The Need of an Analytic Psychiatry", 1927 (Box 64, Folder 1809)
    - "The Problem of Transference", 1927 (Box 64, Folder 1810)
    - "Speaking of Resistances", 1927 (Box 64, Folder 1811)
    - "The Autonomy of the 'I' from the Standpoint of Group Analysis", 1928 (Box 64, Folder 1812)
    - "The Basis of Group-Analysis, or the Analysis of the Reactions of Normal and Neurotic Individuals", 1928 (Box 64, Folder 1813)
    - "Biological Foundations and Mental Methods", 1928 (Box 64, Folder 1814)
    - "Die Laboratoriumsmethode in der Psychoanalyse, ihr Anfang und ihre Entwicklung", 1928 (Box 64, Folder 1815)
    - "The Physiological Basis of Neurosis and Dream", 1930 (Box 64, Folder 1816)
    - "Physiological Behavior-Reactions in the Individual and the Community", 1930 (Box 64, Folder 1817)
    - "So-Called 'Normal' Social Relationships Expressed in the Individual and the Group, and their Bearing on the Problems of Neurotic Disharmonies", 1930 (Box 64, Folder 1818)
    - "Physiologische Verhaltensreaktionen in Individuum und in der Gesellschaft", 1932 (Box 64, Folder 1819)
    - "Réactions physiologiques du comportement individual et collectif", 1932 (Box 64, Folder 1820)
    - "Crime and the Social Reaction of Right and Wrong", 1933 (Box 64, Folder 1821)
    - "The Morphology of Insanity as a Racial Process: A Study of Attention in Relation to Adaptive Disorders", 1933 (Box 64, Folder 1822)
    - "A Phylogenetic Study of Insanity in Its Underlying Morphology", 1933-1934 (Box 64, Folder 1823)
    - "Behavior Mechanisms and their Phylo-Pathology", 1935 (Box 64, Folder 1824)
    - "Fallacies of the Senses", 1935 (Box 64, Folder 1825)
    - "Neuropathology and the Internal Environment", 1935 (Box 64, Folder 1826)
    - "Altering Frames of Reference in the Sphere of Human Behavior", 1937 (Box 64, Folder 1827)
    - "The Law of the Organism: A Neuro-Social Approach to the Problems of Human Behavior", 1937 (Box 64, Folder 1828)
    - "The Organism as a Whole and its Phyloanalytic Implications", 1937 (Box 64, Folder 1829)
    - "The Organismic Factor in Disorders of Behavior", 1937 (Box 64, Folder 1830)
    - "Bio-Physical Factors in Relation to Functional Imbalances", 1938 (Box 64, Folder 1831)
    - "Kymograph Studies of Physiological (Respiratory) Concomitants in Two Types of Attentional Adaptation", 1938 (Box 64, Folder 1832)
    - "The Lifwynn Foundation: An Organismic Study of Behavior in the Individual and in the Community", 1938 (Box 64, Folder 1833)
    - "The Economic Factor in Disorders of Behavior", 1939 (Box 64, Folder 1834)
    - "The World as Will", 1939 (Box 64, Folder 1835)
    - "The Human Equation", 1941 (Box 64, Folder 1836)
    - "Kymograph Records of Neuromuscular (Respiratory) Patterns in Relation to Behavior Disorders", 1941 (Box 64, Folder 1837)
    - "Neurosis and War: A Problem in Human Behavior", 1941 (Box 64, Folder 1838)
    - "The Neurodynamics of Behavior", 1943 (Box 65, Folder 1839)
    - "Preliminary Report of Electroencephalographic Recordings in Relation to Behavior Modifications", 1943 (Box 65, Folder 1840)
    - "Electroencephalographic Recordings of Varying Aspects of Attention in Relation to Behavior", 1945 (Box 65, Folder 1841)
    - "Phylobiology: Behavior Reactions in the Individual and the Community", 1946 (Box 65, Folder 1842)
    - "The Social Neurosis: A Study in 'Clinical Anthropology'", 1949 (Box 65, Folder 1843)
    - "Studies with the Lifwynn Eye-Movement Camera"., 1949 (Box 65, Folder 1844)
    - "Two Modes of Social Adaptation and their Concomitants in Ocular Movements" with Hans C. Syz, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 1845)
    - "Emotion and the Social Crisis: A Problem in Phylobiology", 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1846)
    - "Prescription for Peace: The Biological Basis of Man's Ideological Conflicts", 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1847)
    - Über Phylopathologie und Psychoanalyse: Eine Physiologische Deutung der Gestörten Sozialen Interreaktionen, undated (Box 65, Folder 1848)
    - The Social Basis of Consciousness, 1927 (Box 65, Folder 1849)
    - The Structure of Insanity, 1932 (Box 65, Folder 1850)
    - The Biology of Human Conflict, 1937 (Box 65, Folder 1851)
    - The Neurosis of Man: An Introduction to A Science of Human Behavior, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 1852)
    - Science and Man's Behavior: The Contribution of Phylobiology, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 1853)
    - A Search for Man's Sanity: The Selected Letters of Trigant Burrow, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 1854)
    - Preconscious Foundations of Human Experience, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 1855)
    - Toward Social Sanity and Human Survival, edited by Alfreda Sill Galt, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 1856)
  - Manuscripts of Published Works
    - Publication reports, 1926-1927 (Box 68, Folder 1857)
    - Published and unpublished writings, List of, 1929-1934 (Box 68, Folder 1858)
    - Words and phrases, 1924-1945, undated (Box 68, Folder 1859)
    - Manuscripts, where sent, 1927-1928 (Box 68, Folder 1860)
    - "The Autonomy of the 'I' from the Standpoint of Group Analysis:" abstract, undated (Box 68, Folder 1861)
    - "The Basis of Group-Analysis or the Analysis of the Reactions of Normal and Neurotic Individuals", undated (Box 68, Folder 1862-1863)
    - "Behavior Mechanisms and their Phylo-pathology", undated (Box 68, Folder 1864)
    - "Bio-Physical Factors in Relation to Functional Imbalances:" abstract, undated (Box 68, Folder 1865)
    - "Crime and the Social Reaction of Right and Wrong", 1929 (Box 68, Folder 1866-1867)
    - "The Determination of the Position of a Momentary Impression in the Temporal Course:" Burrow Ph.D. dissertation, 1909 (Box 68, Folder 1868)
    - "The Economic Factor in Disorders of Behavior", 1938 (Box 68, Folder 1869)
    - "Electroencephalographic Recordings of Varying Aspects of Attention in Relation to Behavior Disorders", 1943 (Box 68, Folder 1870)
    - "Emotion and the Social Crisis", 1948, undated (Box 68, Folder 1871)
    - "Fallacies of the Senses", 1932-1935 (Box 68, Folder 1872-1874)
    - "The Genesis and Meaning of 'Homosexuality' and Its Relation to the Problem of Introverted Mental States", 1914 (Box 68, Folder 1875)
    - "The Group Method of Analysis", 1925 (Box 68, Folder 1876-1878)
    - "The Hero", 1924 (Box 68, Folder 1879)
    - "The Heroic Role", 1925 (Box 68, Folder 1880-1881)
    - "The Human Equation", undated (Box 69, Folder 1882)
    - "Instrumental Measurements as an Aid in Differentiating Deviate from Healthy Behavior Mechanisms", 1938 (Box 69, Folder 1883)
    - "Kymograph Records of Neuromuscular (Respiratory) Patterns in Relation to Behavior Disorders", 1938-1940 (Box 69, Folder 1884)
    - "The Laboratory Method in Psychoanalysis", undated (Box 69, Folder 1885)
    - Mental Health, editorials from, 1923-1926 (Box 69, Folder 1886)
    - "Morphology of Insanity as a Racial Process", 1932 (Box 69, Folder 1887)
    - "The Need for an Analytic Psychiatry", 1926-1927 (Box 69, Folder 1888-1889)